[Episode 7]
The Imperial Exam fraud
is the fault of the Ministry of Rites.
My mistake caused you to suffer.
If you truly wish to repay me,
then take good care of yourself
and prepare well for the exam.
I remember when we were in Shazhou,
you gave me a chance,
but I refused your kind offer.
Now I understand.
In this cruel world,
holding onto lofty ideals can be fatal.
I'm afraid
that one day, even you couldn't protect me.
I still remember
the Meng Ting Hui from Shazhou.
She was full of high spirits
and grand strategies.
Her Huiyuan policy essay was even sharper,
and she had even greater ambition.
Now that I am by your side,
you don't need to live in fear.
I look forward to you
holding the reins of power,
serving the court
and bringing prosperity to the people.
Do you really believe I can do it?
I believe
Meng Ting Hui who debated state affairs
with me in Shazhou.
Then can I still call you He Du?
Fu Zhi, I must seize power,
so that I can protect you and avenge myself.
But my own strength alone
is too insignificant.
If I want to stay in the capital,
I must use my friendship with He Du
to get closer to him.
But the Emperor's mind is unfathomable,
and my future remains uncertain.
While recovering in the palace,
I will prepare for the Palace Exam.
I miss you. Don't worry about me.
[Chaoxin Garden]
So Miss Meng and His Majesty
have such a history.
No wonder His Majesty insisted on
bringing her back for treatment despite objections.
What are you so envious of?
Do you also dream
of winning a beauty's heart?
- You!
- Nian, Zhi Shu.
What are you talking about?
Nian is yearning for love.
Nonsense!
Then why are you so worked up?
Nian, you've grown up.
Which girl has caught your eye?
Tell me, and I will go ask
Father and Mother
propose the marriage for you.
I spend all day in the military camp.
How could any girl catch my eyes?
But you've been in the palace for many days.
Mother and I are missing you.
Miss Meng has now fully recovered,
so I don't need to stay with her today.
Zhi Li, His Majesty and Miss Meng
encountered in Shazhou.
They share a life-and-death bond.
That's why His Majesty
takes special care of her.
I know all this.
What do you mean by that?
We grew up with His Majesty since childhood.
He takes special care of you as well.
Now that he's reached the age
to choose an Empress.
Don't you want to be the Empress?
You! Shen Zhi Shu!
What's wrong with you?
His Majesty and I are not real siblings,
but we are closer than that.
Just like Nian and me,
we'll always be brother and sister.
It seems I couldn't be the Empress's brother.
Zhi Li, you've been working hard these days.
Today I can go home early
and make your favorite lotus leaf chicken.
No need. I have to go see Master first.
I might return late.
Tell Mother for me. I'm leaving.
I wonder
what's so interesting about that old man.
He's so bookish.
Only Zhi Li likes to listen to him.
What about you? You happen to be free today,
and I haven't had
lotus leaf chicken in a long time.
I'll try your cooking.
I have official duties to do.
Go eat it by yourself.
I won't be back until tomorrow morning.
You two have passed the Metropolitan Exam.
I have prepared a gift for you.
I hope you achieve excellent results
in the Palace Exam.
It's the Four Treasures of the Study
from Shanlian House.
This Hu brush and Hui inkstick
are both of top quality.
Thank you, Master.
Zhi Li.
This is a seal Master carved for Zhi Li?
Seal carving takes many days.
Did you finish it
before the Metropolitan Exam?
Were you not afraid I wouldn't pass?
I trust you.
You have outstanding talent
and unique insight.
The court needs people of vision like you.
Thank you. I will treasure it.
Honey.
Greetings, Madam.
Since my husband is
celebrating his students' success today,
as his wife, I should also come
to offer my congratulations.
Zhi Li, do you like the seal?
He carved it for days,
making his eyes sore badly.
I had to massage them every day
just to help him see clearly.
This seal is a small gift from both of us.
Thank you for your kindness, Madam.
Honey, you must take good care of yourself,
or else I couldn't rest well either.
You two truly share a deep, loving bond.
It makes us quite envious.
You will all start your own families.
My husband instructs you in your studies,
and I could help you
navigate the important matters of life.
Especially you, Zhi Li.
If there's someone you like,
you must tell me.
Thank you, Madam.
Alright, I have matters to attend to.
You may go back now.
We take our leave.
At home, you won't even
bother to bring a cup of tea.
Yet today, you carved a seal for someone.
Aren't you afraid of hurting your hands?
Look at you.
Is there a trace
of the noble lady you once were?
Are you saying I'm not as young
and beautiful as I used to be?
You are the one who changed first.
Enough.
I have official business to attend to.
Dou Kou, look at him.
He's getting more and more impatient with me.
Everyone, guess what this is.
This is the legendary Pearl Whitening Powder
that makes one adorable and likable.
Pearl Whitening Powder!
Hua Rong, last time you told me
you wanted to be prettier and fair-skinned.
After I went back,
I pondered it day and night,
working hard
and even skipping meals and sleep.
And I finally developed
this exclusive balm just for you.
Apply it twice daily
in the morning and evening.
And I guarantee your face
will become smooth, flawless,
and delicate.
Everyone will adore and like you.
- I want one too.
- Me too.
I have enough for everyone. Take it easy.
I have enough for everyone.
Pharmacist Yin,
you have quite a leisurely job.
You come to our place
whenever you have free time.
If someone finds out,
you'll surely get a beating.
It's a good thing.
Otherwise, he wouldn't have time
to make balms and powders for us.
- Exactly!
- Right!
So, everyone, feel free to buy more.
Next up is the last balm of the day,
Magnolia Balm.
Apply it all over your body every night,
and I guarantee you'll wake up
smelling fragrant and with beautiful skin.
It only costs five taels.
It costed three taels the day before.
Why does it cost five taels now?
Is it expensive? Five taels
can make you beautiful and fragrant.
You can have a good mood every single day.
Do you think
you're just buying the Magnolia Balm?
No! You're fighting for beauty.
Come here. Let me tell you a secret.
Do you know Miss Meng,
who's been staying in the palace these days?
Even she is a regular customer
of my Magnolia Balm.
Otherwise, she couldn't
stay in the palace for so long.
You know what I mean. I couldn't say more.
Just buy it.
- I want one.
- Me too.
I have enough for everyone.
Here. This is yours.
- Give it to me first.
- It's mine.
Next time,
I'll make exclusive balms just for you all.
Okay!
This smells so good.
It smells so good.
- Let's go.
- Good.
Miss, you look unfamiliar.
I have the Pearl Whitening Powder here
that makes one adorable and likable.
Would you like one?
Is Miss Meng really your regular customer?
That's a secret between Miss Meng and me.
Miss Meng is a regular buyer
of my Pearl Whitening Powder.
Even His Majesty uses it.
Miss Meng bought it for His Majesty.
She begged me for a long time
before I agreed to sell it to her.
Then I'll buy what Miss Meng bought.
This is the last one.
You are smart,
willing to pay for your own beauty.
Fixed price, twenty taels.
The price isn't
what you just charged those ladies.
A thing is priced high if it is rare.
This is the last bottle. Buy it now,
then you can become more beautiful
and meet your ideal husband soon.
I'm about the same age as you.
No need to flatter me.
I didn't bring any taels.
Come with me to get them.
Let me tell you, Miss Meng always praises me.
I'll go back and try it.
Miss, I just remembered
I have some urgent business.
You can pay me later. I'll be going now.
Miss Meng, what are you doing here?
Miss Meng? I'll be leaving now.
Lord, I caught a swindler.
He sold overpriced cosmetics
to the palace ladies. Please deal with him.
It's a misunderstanding.
It's all a misunderstanding.
Miss Meng,
if you like anything in my bag, just take it.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
We are acquaintances. I'll see her off.
Well, it's you again.
Flog him five times.
It's a misunderstanding.
It's a misunderstanding, Captain Di.
Do you need
any of that Pearl Whitening Powder?
How about giving you for free forever?
Lord Xu, you claim to respect me,
yet you abolished the Imperial Exam for Women
before reporting to me.
Has the court become a place
where only your voice is heard?
Please calm your anger, Your Majesty.
I speak for the Six Ministries
and hundreds of Ning Empire's officials.
This exam fraud
has thrown the capital into chaos.
The Laws of Ning Empire clearly states
that the chief examiner has the authority
to abolish the exam due to major fraud.
I was merely acting according to the law.
Well said.
The late Emperor granted you this dragon staff
to assist me, not to govern in my stead.
I have a clear conscience.
When you were still the Crown Prince,
you studied the "Model of the Emperor" at eight
and learned how to govern the nation at twelve.
I taught you wholeheartedly.
Everything I do now
is for you and for the court,
without the slightest selfish motive.
I've had enough of your rhetoric.
I wanted to reform the grain transport system,
and you called it risky.
I wanted to reorganize the Imperial Guard,
and you called it radical.
Now I want to establish the Imperial Exam,
and you forcibly abolished it.
In your eyes, are all my decisions wrong?
Your Majesty, when you were the Crown Prince,
I taught you
that a ruler must have his own opinions.
Now that you truly have your own opinions,
you despise me instead.
By defending
the Imperial Exam for Women this time,
do you really think
I am too old and incompetent to assist you?
What the Ning Empire needs is never a ruler
who merely maintains the conventions.
Lord Xu, you should have let go long ago.
It was precisely because
I let go for a moment
that the Imperial Exam for Women
became a mess.
Today, I insist on being
a disobedient minister.
As long as I have this dragon staff,
the Imperial Exam for Women
must be abolished.
I second.
[Permanently Abolish
the Imperial Exam for Women]
In the half year since I ascended the throne,
the nation is stable
and everything is renewed.
I now establish the Imperial Exam for Women
to select talent based solely on merit.
Father, Mother.
Lord Xu has dominated
the court for many years.
Key positions in the Six Ministries
are all filled by members of his faction.
Though I have inherited the throne,
my decrees struggle to be executed.
This time, disregarding all objections,
I am restarting the Imperial Exam for Women,
using it as a sword to break this stalemate.
[Imperial Library]
Everyone, His Majesty is approaching.
Please leave immediately.
[Laws of Ning Empire]
Are you looking for the Laws of Ning Empire?
So audacious, Meng Ting Hui!
How dare you to trespass
in the Imperial Library
and hide here when Chief Steward You
dismissed everyone else?
I've heard this place holds vast knowledge.
Today, I am here to see it with my own eyes.
Since no one stopped me,
how can it be trespassing?
Besides, I was reading in the corner
and didn't see Chief Steward You.
With the Imperial Exam for Women abolished,
what are you still reading for?
I think you aren't truly willing
to abolish the exam.
Naturally, I must follow your decree
and prepare for the exam well,
instead of following the order of Lord Xu.
Smooth talker.
It seems you have recovered.
Your weak physique
from days ago is also gone.
I was physically and mentally exhausted,
and drank too much back then.
It's true that I lost my composure.
But the courage I shared with He Du
when facing life and death is also true.
I wonder which side of me you prefer.
Those selected for the Imperial Exam
must withstand scrutiny in every aspect.
I think He Du in Shazhou
was more interesting than you are now.
Do you know
I hate being schemed against most?
I never scheme, but to relieve your worries.
This game of chess is at a stalemate,
with both sides equally matched.
You want me to lose?
In some games, losing is winning.
Don't you know what I'm best at
is breaking the stalemate?
This move on the center point
is played brilliantly.
Since Lord Xu likes to reason
and apply pressure
[Laws of Ning Empire]
by using the Laws of Ning Empire.
We can break this stalemate
by treating him with courtesy.
Lord Xu has announced the abolition
of the Imperial Exam for Women.
By now, I presume
many students are on their way home.
Meng Ting Hui, I'd like to see
if you can convince Lord Xu.
I'm of little influence
and have no acquaintances in the capital.
And I'm not your minister.
Lord Gu can be of use.
[Gu Mansion]
Lord Gu, Madam invites you
to have dinner with her.
I still have things to do. Let her eat first.
Lord Gu, Madam cooked today.
She has been busy preparing
a table of delicacies all day.
Please come with me.
Honey, you're here.
This is a meal I specially prepared for you.
I didn't expect
it would be so difficult to invite you.
I have many affairs to handle recently.
No matter how busy you are,
you must take care of yourself.
Don't stay in the study tonight.
With the Imperial Exam for Women abolished,
I need to deal with many issues.
You should rest first.
You're skipping the meal and sleep for work.
Is it all for Shen Zhi Li, isn't it?
Well, it was wise of you
to have her enter the palace.
She and His Majesty
used to be childhood sweethearts.
If they spend day and night together,
she might soon become the Empress.
Nonsense!
The emperor-minister affair warrants execution
of nine clans according to our ancestral precept.
Are you trying to destroy the Shen family?
Don't ever say that again.
I am just planning for your sake.
Shen Zhi Li is your most prized student.
If she were to become the Empress,
you could become the first chancellor
of Ning Empire sooner.
His Majesty's marriage concerns the nation.
How could you make such remarks?
It's strange.
Every time Shen Zhi Li is mentioned,
you lose your composure like this.
Le Yan is different from you.
She has aspirations,
aiming to debate politics in the court.
How could she be willing
to be confined to the harem?
Are you despising me
for having no aspirations?
What's the point of being female officials?
Nowadays, all female officials
in the court hold sinecures.
They all hope to resign
and marry someone decent.
Is she never going
to marry in her entire life?
Besides,
the one she would marry is His Majesty.
What is there for you
to be dissatisfied with?
It's not our place
to discuss how His Majesty thinks.
If you have nothing to do,
go to the theater and watch a play.
Mind your words.
What kind of wine is this?
This is the potent tonic wine
I had Dou Kou prepare.
Honey, just stay here tonight.
Look at him now.
He's forgotten his own origins.
How dare he scowl at me every day?
Madam, please calm down.
Pour the wine away.
Yes.
[Chunman House]
Since Lord Xu forcibly abolished
the Imperial Exam for Women,
female students from various prefectures
have gone to my residence.
I have been refusing all invitations.
And I only made an exception
to accept this invitation for you.
I know you are in a difficult position.
Today, I brought someone
to help share your burden.
This is...
I am Meng Ting Hui. Greetings, Lord Gu.
Le Yan, I know you've been taking care
of Miss Meng in the palace recently.
You brought her here
to discuss the Imperial Exam for Women, right?
Exactly.
Lord Gu,
I have studied the Laws of Ning Empire for days
and figured out a solution,
which can refute Lord Xu's memorial
to abolish the Imperial Exam for Women.
However, we need your help.
Absurd!
Le Yan, I know you want
to restore the Imperial Exam for Women.
Forgive me. I can't help.
Master, I heard from my father
that you didn't sign Lord Xu's memorial.
Since Lord Xu made up his mind,
whether I signed or not would change nothing.
However,
I have made proper arrangements for you.
Scholar Liu at the Hanlin Academy
is a close acquaintance of mine.
You can go there to study.
Master, I am taking the Imperial Exam,
not to stay in the court
by relying on my origin or your influence.
The Imperial Exam for Women
has been put on hold for nine years.
If it's truly abolished,
there might be no chance to restore it.
Women across the nation will see no future
and can only be trapped within their homes.
If we can stop Lord Xu now,
I am willing to try my best.
I hope you will help me.
That doesn't sound like you.
Meng Ting Hui, Lord Xu abolished
the Imperial Exam for Women because of you.
Even His Majesty couldn't stop it.
What can we do then?
After you entered the palace,
you drew criticism.
Now you incite Le Yan
to submit a pledge of allegiance.
If all women were to imitate you,
seeking fame and clinging to the powerful,
what would the court become?
What makes you think
I would help you oppose Lord Xu?
At court, the only one
who can stand up to Lord Xu is you, Lord Gu.
But now, the Imperial Exam for Men
is controlled by Lord Xu.
Even with your great achievements,
you are still suppressed by him.
But if you are willing to stand up
for the women across the nation,
in the future court, female officials
will surely be loyal to you.
Lord Gu, why not listen to my plan
before making a decision?
Master, please calm down.
Let's hear Miss Meng's plan first.
The Recommendation System section
of the Laws of Ning Empire states
that to ensure students excel
both academically and morally,
they can be recommended by their hometowns
and mutually guarantee each other.
If we gather recommendation letters
from Women's Academies across the nation,
and then unite the female scholars
to submit a joint petition,
requesting the restoration
of the Imperial Exam for Women
to create a situation
where public opinion cannot be defied.
At that point,
even if Lord Xu can oppose His Majesty,
he cannot oppose all the students.
If you've already planned it all out,
why do you need me?
I can manage the joint petition,
but as for the recommendation letters
from each prefecture,
I am of little influence,
so I can't obtain them.
If you are willing
to proclaim your support for the students,
people would rally behind you in no time.
Master, my father wrote this,
proving this method is viable.
It's been five days.
Miss Meng said she'd get recommendation letters
from Women's Academies and come to us.
But so far, we heard nothing from her.
I'm afraid we wouldn't hear from her.
The court has already announced the abolition
of the Imperial Exam for Women.
Waiting any longer will just be futile.
We've studied hard for years
and finally become scholars,
but the court abolished
the Imperial Exam just like that.
Do we women really have no chance
for the Imperial Exam?
There's hope!
There's hope for us!
By proposing to increase
the allocation of school lands
to benefit the Women's Academies
in every prefecture, Lord Gu obtained for us
a joint recommendation letter
from all the prefectures.
There's hope
for restoring the Imperial Exam for Women.
Great!
Finally, there's hope.
Sign the joint petition now.
Let's go to Lord Xu's residence to demand
the restoration of the Imperial Exam for Women.
Yes!
- I'll go too.
- Me too.
I'll go too.
[Xu Mansion]
We want the exam! We demand to see Lord Xu!
[With literary and military talents,
women can rival any man]
How dare you to cause a disturbance
at the Chancellor's residence!
Drive them all away!
Yes!
We're just petitioning. What crime is it?
What right do you have to drive us away?
Don't fear, everyone.
Anyone who unjustifiably harms a scholar
will be flogged 20 strokes and exiled for a year.
We're not leaving!
Lord Xu arrives.
Lord Xu,
on behalf of all the female scholars
in the Ning Empire,
we are here to petition
with recommendation letters and a joint petition.
Meng Ting Hui, you caused the Huiyuan case
to be known throughout the city.
Now you're inciting female scholars
to besiege my residence.
This is outrageous!
It seems it's right
to abolish the Imperial Exam for Women.
Exam fraud has existed since ancient times.
The perpetrators should be punished.
Why would it block the path
to the career for women?
I dare to ask,
is this truly
for the long-term stability of the nation,
or is it driven by your own selfish motives?
Insolent!
Since the late Emperor
allowed women to become officials,
few female officials has been able
to serve a full term.
They either resigned halfway for their family,
or proved unqualified for the task.
That's why the Imperial Exam for Women
has been put on hold all along.
You entered the harem as a commoner.
Are you truly seeking to become an official,
or trying to curry favor with His Majesty?
Today, I am willing
to stake everything to prove my resolve.
[Meng Ting Hui]
I sign this pledge with blood.
If I fail the Palace Exam,
I am willing to be assigned to the Music Bureau.
Lord Xu, will you restore
the Imperial Exam for Women,
giving justice to the women
across the nation?
Fine. If any of you dares to pledge this,
I will believe you are sincere
about taking the exam.
Why must you implicate others?
In my view,
you female scholars are all just bluffing
without qualifications.
These women think highly of themselves,
but at critical moments, they back down.
How can they bear great responsibilities?
When I bid farewell to my families, I swore
that I would either return home in glory,
or die in a foreign land.
I will sign this pledge.
Miss Meng, I...
Miss Shen, you come from
a prominent family with many connections.
No. I have blood phobia.
This rouge can also prove your sincerity.
Zhi Li comes from a prominent family,
yet she is still willing
to fight for the future of women.
I am in.
Today, we are going all out.
We must not let others look down on us.
Exactly! We can't let them look down on us.
- Yes.
- Exactly.
I'll sign too.
- I'll sign too.
- Me too.
- I'll sign.
Count me in.
- Me too.
- I want to sign too.
I'll sign too.
- Me too.
- I want to sign too.
And me.
[I am willing to sign this pledge with blood]
[If I fail the Palace Exam, I am willing
to be assigned to the Music Bureau. Meng Ting Hui]
The tide turns, and the people follow.
The Women's Academies and their students
have stated their position clearly.
Please give us a chance
to fulfill our aspirations!
Fine. I shall wait and see.
If there's any more trouble,
don't blame me for being merciless.
Wonderful!
You cast your eyes
upon the common folk every day.
But have you ever
viewed the imperial city from here?
If you hadn't invited me today,
having grown up in the imperial palace,
I would've never known such a place.
When you were in Shazhou,
you said freedom is a luxury.
Now I know your true identity.
He Du. "Du" stands for solitude.
I think I understand that as an Emperor,
you can't have true freedom.
Son, do you know what "solitude" means?
The Book of Documents says,
"When the ruler is virtuous,
the whole world follows."
Thus, the Emperor's
solitude is not isolation,
but the weight of the world
rests on your shoulders alone.
Father, please take care of your health.
I-I am afraid...
What are you afraid of? Tell me.
I'm afraid that when I inherit that throne,
I couldn't bear that weight of the world.
I'm afraid of disappointing you and Mother.
I'm even more afraid that from then on,
in this vast imperial palace,
no one will ever love and cherish me
like you and Mother do.
Look up.
The Emperor may bleed or lose his head,
but he must never show weakness.
My son, remember.
The Emperor's solitude means
you must give up your own feelings,
to achieve the greatness for the world.
I prepared the Shaosanbai wine
from Shazhou for you.
After my father admonished me,
I dared not slack off in the slightest.
I haven't even
drunk a single drop of the wine.
I think the late Emperor
gave you the name "Solitude",
not wanting you to be alone all your life.
It was simply
because you were his only child.
No one else but you
are qualified to bear the bitterness,
hardship, and solitude of the Emperor.
You're right. Perhaps this was
my father's expectation of me.
Then I shall break the rule today.
Drinking atop the imperial city at this hour
is a first in my life.
Watching you drink atop the imperial city
is also a first in my life.
You are the first person to make me willing
to break the rule and drink wine.
There are things
even you cannot resolve overnight.
But you can
drink to your heart's content today.
I haven't felt so carefree in a long time.
It seems every time I'm with you,
I can temporarily forget these worries.
Your Majesty,
since my injuries are now fully healed,
it's time for me to leave.
You want to leave the imperial palace?
If I stay in the palace,
even if I rank first in the Palace Exam,
I fear it will still invite criticism.
People might say you showed favoritism.
Do you need it?
I must succeed.
So confident?
Your Majesty,
do you have any arrangement
for the top three candidates in the Palace Exam?
You haven't even passed the exam yet.
How dare you inquire about the arrangement?
If one must first hold the office
before discussing state affairs,
then how did previous sages
earn good reputations for accepting advice?
The Censorate has a special function,
so naturally capable people should fill it.
I am willing to share your burdens.
About the Censorate, it's still in discussion
and hasn't been announced yet.
How did you learn of it?
When passing by the Imperial Garden,
I happened to overhear Grand Tutor Shen
discussing it with you.
You restored the Imperial Exam for Women
precisely to break the old conventions, right?
I boldly say,
if I could be the top scholar, I am willing
to be the sharp sword in your hand.
Meng Ting Hui,
do you really think I will always
tolerate you for overstepping bounds?
Remember, where the sword points
is decided only by the one who wields it.
[Shen Mansion]
Zhi Li, tell me.
At the entrance of the Xu residence today,
did Lord Xu's beard bristle with rage??
We were acting according to the law.
Why do you make it sound like
a street performance?
It's rare for Lord Xu
to make a fool of himself.
I must know some details,
especially since you were there.
- Tell me some details.
- I just remembered
that unfinished game of chess
you left in the study.
We can play chess anytime.
Come on. I want to play now.
- Let's go now.
- Don't...
- Zhi Li!
- Let's go.
Which way did his beard bristle?
Zhi Li, rest well.
Three slices of ginger.
Three red dates.
Three pieces of brown sugar.
Zhi Li.
Come in.
Zhi Li, are you feeling better?
I'm fine.
Well, I heard from the maids
that at this time of the year,
you should drink something to warm up.
Careful, it's hot.
How is it?
Quite sweet. Thank you, Nian.
Then rest well. I'm leaving.